# **AGUSTÍN ARIAS**

#### Mathematician & Data Scientist

@ agustinntarias@gmail.com

♥ Villa Devoto, CABA, Buenos Aires, Argentina

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Masters in Mathematics with experience in teaching mathematics, physics, and computer science at university and high school levels. Passionate about education, with a focus on active learning methodologies and the use of technological tools in the classroom. Additionally, I have professional experience in software production and data science environments.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Data Science Programmer**

#### Independent

2020-Present

- Buenos Aires, Argentina
- Work with OCR tools at library and architectural levels.
- Gained experience in software production environments and privately taught this knowledge to Computer Engineering students at ITBA.
- Tutored first-year Engineering students at UBA.

# Assistant Professor of Mathematics and Physics University of Buenos Aires (UBA)

2021-Present

CABA, Argentina

- Classes and support in Algebra, Physics I, Numerical Calculus, Differential Calculus, and Mathematics I to IV.
- Participation in the organization of science and technology fairs.

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Mathematics University of Buenos Aires (UBA)

□ 2019-2024

CABA, Argentina

#### Specialization in Data Science

#### **Digital House**

**1** 2019-2020

## **SKILLS**

# Languages Python LaTeX C++ Matlab Tools GeoGebra Moodle Jupyter Desmos Matlab

#### Languages



German



Honorable Mention – Argentine Interuniversity Mathematics Competition
2019

Certificate of Proficiency in English (C2)

2018

Goethe-Zertifikat A1 (German)
2017

Gold Medal – National Physics Olympiad 2015